Guide to the Randolph Linsly Simpson African-American Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series I. Visual Material
  - LATER 19TH CENTURY PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Richardson, Artist, no location Mini-photo of child, very young, in white gown, seated in chair. Later 19th century photograph, 2-1/4 x 1-1/2, circa 1898 (Box 17)
      Item #546
    - C. Bau, Greenfield, MA Half length portrait of lady with spectacles, fancy hat, and feather collar. Later 19th century photograph. 3 x 2-1/8, circa 1899 (Box 17)
      Item #547
    - Unknown photographer Gem photo of Emma Blocken; young woman. Later 19th century photograph, 3 x 2, circa 1895 (Box 17)
      Identified in ink, verso.
      Item #548
    - Unknown photographer Man stands a table, high wire fence behind him, various denominations of United States currency stacked on table. Later 19th century photograph, mounted, 5-1/4 x 6-1/4, circa 1898 (Box 17, Folder 786)
      In ink, recto, below photograph, "J. R. Brown in the act of pressing a package of notes." In ink, verso, "John R. Brown. Note-packer. In the act of pressing a package." Also stamped, "Chief Division of Issues. Office of Treasurer U.S."
      Item #549
    - Unknown photographer "Nassau, N.P." (sic) in ink, verso; Three white men in horse drawn carriage, young black driver; cemetery in background. Later 19th century photograph, 5 x 8, 1887 (Box 17, Folder 787)
      All identified in ink, verso.
      Item #550
    - Mugnier, New Orleans, LA One in series of five, "View, Cotton Levee" stamped in negative. Huge bales of cotton, on ground, on wagons pulled by mule teams, riverboats in background. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on orange board, 5 x 8, 1890 (Box 17, Folder 788)
      Item #551
    - Mugnier, New Orleans, LA One in series of five, "No. 672. Cotton Levee, Canal St." stamped in negative. Bales of cotton; mule teams hitched to wagons; men at work and standing by. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on orange board, 5 x 8., circa 1890 (Box 17, Folder 789)
      Item #552
    - Mugnier, New Orleans, LA One in series of five, "No. 553. Str. E.J. Gay, Loading." Barrels, crates, sacks of goods being loaded from pier onto riverboat. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on orange board, 5 x 8, circa 1890 (Box 17, Folder 790)
      Item #553
    - Mugnier, New Orleans, LA One in series of five, "Boats Loading." stamped into negative. Seven riverboats lined up at pier being loaded with goods stacked on pier and from wagons drawn by mule teams. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on orange board, 5 x 8, circa 1898 (Box 17, Folder 791)
      Item #554
    - Mugnier, New Orleans, LA One in series of five, "No. 552. Str. Jno. W. Cannon Loading." Three riverboats: John W. Cannon, John H. Hanna, third is partially out of frame, being loaded with goods and passengers. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on orange board, 5 x 8, circa 1890 (Box 17, Folder 792)
      Item #555
    - Russell Brothers, Anniston, AL Men, women, and children picking cotton in field, buildings in background. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on light cream colored board, 5 x 8, circa 1898 (Box 17, Folder 793)
      In negative, "182. Russell Bros. Photo." Stamped verso, "Special Southern Views" with list and descriptions of each photo in series. In ink along outer edge, "Cotton Picking in Alexandria Valley, Alabama." Both this and 557 from same series.
      Item #556
    - Russell Brothers, Anniston, AL Man, women, and children picking cotton. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on light cream colored card, 5 x 8, circa 1898 (Box 17, Folder 794)
      Stamped verso, "Special Southern Views" with list and descriptions of each photo in series.
      Item #557
    - Unknown photographer Group portrait: 11 women, 4 men pose before building with broken window. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on dark green board, 5-1/8 x 8-3/8, circa 1890 (Box 17, Folder 795)
      Item #558
    - Unknown photographer Group photograph, 9 children, many barefoot, sitting on step; fence at right. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on dark green board, 5-1/8 x 8-3/8, circa 1890 (Box 17, Folder 796)
      Item #559
    - S.J. Morrow, Orlando, FL "The Noyes Place in Altamonte Springs, Fla." Portly man stands at wire fence right, looking left, watching men cultivate orchard around large house. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on neutral card, 5-1/4 x 8-1/2, circa 1890 (Box 17, Folder 797)
      Identified in pencil verso.
      Item #560
    - Unknown photographer Public Square St. Augustine, FL with view of Old Slave Market and Confederate Market, foreground; St Augustine Hotel and Spanish Cathedral, background. Later 19th century photograph, mounted, 6-1/2 x 9-1/2, circa 1895 (Box 17, Folder 798)
      Item #561
    - Unknown photographer Full length double portrait, boy and girl stand barefoot in small clearing. Later 19th century photograph, mounted, 5-1/3 x 4-1/4, circa 1898 (Box 17, Folder 799)
      Item #562
    - Unknown photographer Exterior view looking east from railroad tracks down middle of Main Street, Athens, LA. Houses line both sides of street: "Baker Bros" closest merchant on left; towns people, horses, wagons, etc lined up from one side of street to the other. Later 19th century photograph, mounted, 8 x 10, circa 1898 (Box 17, Folder 800)
      Item #563
    - Unknown photographer "Albert Lawrence de Manfredy, Coast and Geodetic Survey Party." Group portrait of men in camp in forest. Later 19th century photograph, mounted 7-1/2 x 7-1/2, circa 1898 (Box 17, Folder 801)
      Identified in ink verso.
      Item #564
    - Unknown photographer Group of black children seated in a row on curb; white children stand against stone house dwarfed by larger wooden building on left. Later 19th century photograph, mounted on neutral board, 4-3/4 x 6-5/8, circa 1895 (Box 17, Folder 802)
      In ink, recto, beneath photograph, "Richmond, Va. (Washington's Headquarters)." Unlisted photo, verso; wide cobblestone boulevard, building at end; Leisfner's Hotel at left; people look from windows and stand on sidewalk in front.
      Item #565a
    - Unknown photographer Young lady in dress with gigot sleeves stands with left hand on chair back. Later 19th century photograph, mounted, 6-1/2 x 5-1/4, circa 1895 (Box 17, Folder 803)
      Item #565b
    - Unknown photographer Two wheel cart full of household possessions, hitched to mule; woman and child sit atop the possessions, man holds reins. Later 19th century photograph, 3-7/8 x 4-7/8, undated (Box 17, Folder 804)
      In pencil, verso, "Richmond, VA."
      Item #565c
    - Unknown photographer Family group, two women and three children in doorway of clapboard house. Later 19th century photograph, mounted, 5-1/2 x 4-1/2, circa 1895 (Box 17)
      In pencil, verso, "Richmond, VA"
      Item #565d
    - E. Powell, New York "Anti-Slavery Constitutional Amendment Picture:" Oval mosaic of bust length portraits, each in its own printed oval, of President Lincoln, Vice President Hamlin and Senators and Representatives who supported the Constitutional Amendment prohibiting slavery. Later 19th century photograph, framed, 12-7/8 x 11-3/4, 1863
      Key to identity of those photographed verso.
      Item #654b
    - Alexander Gardner, Washington, D.C. "Incidents of the War" series; "What Do I Want, John Henry?", Albumen print, framed Approx. 7 x 8-3/4, 1865 (Box 17, Folder 805)
      In orange pencil, recto, under print, "Warrenton, Va. Nov. 1862"
      Item #1971
    - B.F.K. Rives, Women's Suffrage Association Convention Seneca Falls, New York. Large elegantly dressed crowd on porch of a hotel. Albumen Print, framed 7 x 9-1/4, 1883
      Photographer identified by very faint blind stamp. Frederick Douglass, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Susan B. Anthony can all be identified.
      Item #1972
    - Unknown photographer (Rudolf Eickemeyer?) Young boy in corduroy hat and plaid sweater and candy cane in his mouth standing in woods, Late 19th century photograph 11 x 8-1/4, circa 1899 (Box 17, Folder 806)
      Item #1973
    - Unknown photographer Military banquet in a drill hall; Late 19th century photograph, matted, 6-1/2 x 8-1/2, 1893 July 6
      Date and indecipherable identification in pencil, verso.
      Item #1979
    - T.H. O'Sullivan, no location Two boys prepare to release cocks in space before tents as officers and civilians look on. Bettman Archive reproduction, 8 X 10, 1864 August (Box 17, Folder 807)
      In ink, verso, "Cockfighting at General Orlando B. Wilcox's head quarters before Petersburg. Photo by T.H. O'Sullivan, Aug. 1964."
      Item #1988
    - Unknown photographer Officers seated at field table beneath trees with food and drink; men and tents in background., circa 1893 (Box 17, Folder 808)
      Typescript verso, "Officers' Mess, Company F, 93rd New York Infantry, U.S.A. Headquarters, Army of the Potomac, August, 1863. Civil War."
      Item #1989
    - Unknown photographer Group photograph of F Troop, 11th Cavalry (Artillery?), U.S.Army, depicted in front of a field stone monument and displaying two pennons fastened together at the points. Late 19th century photograph 7-5/8 x 9-5/8, circa 1899 (Box 17, Folder 809)
      Item #2027
    - M.T. Sheahan, Boston "Young Coons:" Half tone, half length of two young black children in pile of raw cotton, framed 13-3/4 round, circa 1895
      Item #2041
    - C.L. Howe & Son, Brattleboro, VT Exterior view of large group of men and women, many with tennis rackets: ivy covered wall of institutional building in background. Late 19C. photograph 5-1/4 x 8-1/2, circa 1890 (Box 17, Folder 810)
      Among the few identified, two black men: Thos. E. Sherman, John J. Smallwood.
      Item #2053
    - George Parker, Niagara Falls, NY "Negro Quarters in St. Augustine." Family group outside doorway to addition of clapboard house. Late 19C. Photograph 5 x 4, 1886 (Box 17, Folder 811)
      Dated from copyright. Title in ink verso.
      Item #2054
    - Unknown photographer Horse drawn dray of Geo. W. Moseley & Son; Hartford and Enflied, CT beside train; Southern Railway freight car immediately behind, Late 19C. photograph, matted, 8 X 10, circa 1895 (Box 17, Folder 812)
      Item #2055
    - Unknown photographer Formal group portrait of "That So Different Four:" two men and two women depicted looking at an issue of "Player" Magazine; one man seated in front wears "blackface" makeup. Late 19C. photograph 9-1/4 x 8, circa 1895 (Box 17, Folder 813)
      Identified in ink, recto, beneath subject.
      Item #2056
    - Swarthout "I's a little Alabama Coon." Young boy in tattered clothes, cap, seated on wood crate marked 'Baker & Co., Ltd., Dorchester, Mass' strumming a homemade banjo, Late 19th century photograph, framed, 14 x 11-1/8, 1897
      Title recto, in negative, bottom of print. Copyright date and signature also in negative.
      Item #2059
    - Wm. Weiss & Co., no location "Blind Musician and his Children"; elderly man wearing straw hat and black suit standing outdoors on sidewalk. He strums a large banjo; to his left a young girl with cape and hat plays a tambourine; to his right are twins, boy and girl, about four years old, both with large hats, one plays a triangle, the other a drum. There is a house with a porch in background, and all figures stand in front of a large tree. Late 19th century photograph, mounted 8-1/2 x 11, undated (Box 18, Folder 814)
      Identification, number "67" and indecipherable text in negative, bottom of subject.
      Item #2060
    - C.E. Waterman, Brooklyn, NY Group of school children with teachers depicted outside "old East Haven school on Main Street." Late 19th century photograph, mounted, 7 x 9. Photographer identified recto below subject, 1883-84 (Box 18, Folder 815)
      Photographer identified recto on mount, below subject. All subjects identified in list of names typed on page and glued verso.
      Item #2061
    - Unknown photographer Young school children, standing outside in front of brick school house. Late 19th century photograph, mounted and matted, 7-1/2 x 10-1/4, circa 1895 (Box 18, Folder 816)
      In pencil, verso: "Willimantic, CT."
      Item #2062
    - Old Dominion G...[cut off], Rich... [cut off] Bust portrait of young woman in fancy dress, with jet beadwork, white blouse with diamond brooch, large hat with buckle and flowing feathers. Late 19th century photograph 6 x 4-1/4, undated (Box 18, Folder 817)
      Item #2065
    - Unknown photographer Three black men with shovels and one white man, all standing by a handcar; building with undecipherable sign at right. Late 19th century photograph 8 x 10, mounted on board, circa 1895 (Box 18, Folder 818)
      Item #2127
    - Unknown Photographer Large group of men: two foreground left pretend to box. Horses in background; sharpening wheels in foreground. Some men hold shears. Late 19th century photograph 8 x 10, circa 1895 (Box 18, Folder 819)
      Item #2128
    - Alexander Gardner, Washington, D.C. "Scene in Pleasant Valley Maryland, No. 24, October 1862." Three Union officers with their wives seated on porch steps, bearded man in civilian clothes stands; black woman with bandanna and large white apron stands at left. 19th century photograph, mounted, 13 x 17-3/4, 1862 October
      Item #2129
    - Edwards & Son Crowd in street and on curb; carriage passes in foreground. 19th century photograph, mounted, 4 X 7, circa 1870 (Box 18, Folder 820)
      "Election Day, Atlanta, GA" in pencil verso.
      Item #2130
    - Reckling, Columbia, SC "Master and Former Slave:" elderly bearded man wearing hat seated in chair beside house, both hands outstretched and clasped by elderly black man standing; three hounds in yard. Platinum print 5 x 8-1/4, undated (Box 18, Folder 821)
      In ink, verso, "Mr. Taylor (... the City of Columbia) his faithful old body servant."
      Item #2131
    - Arthur L. Macbeth, Charleston, SC School group: many children at windows, on porch, and in front of house with picket fence. Albumen print, 5 x 7, circa 1875 (Box 18, Folder 822)
      Item #2132
    - Unknown Photographer Washington's tomb: old man, hat off, stands near entrance. Late 19th century photograph, mounted, 5 x 7, circa 1885 (Box 18, Folder 823)
      Item #2133
    - George Barker, Niagara Falls, NY Street scene in St. Augustine, Florida: Men with two wheel horse carts. Late 19th century photograph, 5 x 4, 1886 (Box 18, Folder 824)
      Duplicate.
      Item #2134
    - J. H. Tarbell, Asheville, N.C. Four children by a board fence, two white, two black, Platinum print, 5-3/4 x 8-1/4, framed. Identity of photographer and date, printed label verso, 1897
      Item #2135
    - Capital City View Co., Springfield, MA School grouped on steps of brick building. Late 19th century photograph, matted, 11 x 9, circa 1895 (Box 18, Folder 825)
      Item #2136
    - Ira F. Collins, Huntsville, AL "On the Shady Side:" Studio set: old man in rags with hat and stick seated, leans against gnarled tree (prop), napping. Albumen print, 8 x 5-1/4, mounted, undated (Box 18, Folder 826)
      Item #2137
    - Buss Studio, Brinkley, AR Large school group seated and standing by school building. Late 19th century photograph, mounted, 7 x 9, circa 1895 (Box 18, Folder 827)
      Item #2138
    - Unknown Photographer Group of workers assembled before building; painted on side of building: "Sarven's Patent Wheel and Rim Bending Department." Later 19th Century photograph, mounted, 8-1/4 x 11-1/2, undated (Box 18, Folder 828)
      Item #2194
    - Copy photograph Frederick Douglass, seated, with grandson Joseph. 19th Century photograph, 10 x 8, circa 1893 (Box 18, Folder 829)
      Item #2196
    - Unknown photographer Group portrait of Company E, 4th U.S. Colored Infantry. Soldiers with muskets standing at ease. Barracks behind them. 19th century photograph, mounted, 9 x 11, undated (Box 18, Folder 830)
      Identified recto, in pencil.
      Item #2205
  - 20TH CENTURY PHOTOGRAPHS
    Subjects in photographs from the twentieth century include industrial workers, municipal employees, and railroad employees, as well as members of lodges, civic and business organizations. Individual portraits and those of couples young and old are chiefly unidentified; prominent politicians, educators, and artists and entertainers are among the easily recognizable figures. School photographs include athletic teams as well as individual graduation portraits, and while most are from New England, images from Baltimore, Maryland, Birmingham, Alabama, and Howard University are also present. Also included are views of Army and Navy personnel during World War II, a parade of black veterans of the Spanish American War, and images of the Wilkins Guard of the Connecticut National Guard.
    Images from the later twentieth century are primarily press photographs with placement information attached. Many are from the Hartford Courant or other local photographic services in the Northeast and Mid-Atlantic regions. Others were published by the Associated Press and United Press International. These include publicity stills of entertainers and other prominent personalities, but many of the images document events of local or national interest, including the wedding of Madame C. J. Walker's granddaughter, the eightieth anniversary celebration of a local church, Thurgood Marshall's appointment to the Supreme Court, and Louis Armstrong presenting Duke Ellington with awards from the Down Beat critics poll. Images of the 1970 NBA and NCAA Men's Basketball championships are among the few relating to athletes.
    - Unknown photographer Civilian band: men, boy and dog; large brick building background, left. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 8 x 9-7/8, circa 1900 (Box 18, Folder 831)
      In pencil, verso, "Pittsburgh."
      Item #566
    - Gilbert's Studio, Philadelphia, PA University of Pennsylvania, Dr. Alfred Stengel Clinic of Medicine: gurney with patient, nurse, doctors, foreground; auditorium partly filled with young men in suits taking notes. Early 20th century photograph, mounted 13-1/4 x 17, circa 1905
      Identified in ink below photograph. Two plaques on wall in memoriam to "Dr. John Herr Musser" and "Dr. A. O.J. Kelly."
      Item #567
    - G. Fox & Co. (?) Large group of postmen in uniform stand before municipal building. Wreath and "25" on caps. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 9 x 11, circa 1910 (Box 18, Folder 832)
      Item #568
    - Leopold, New Haven, CT One in series of five, "The Wilkins Guard, Co. A. 5th Battalion, Connecticut National Guard." Group portrait: drummer to right, barracks in background. Early 20th century photograph, framed. 6-3/4 x 8-3/4, 1907 (Box 18, Folder 833)
      Studio identified in blind engraving recto. Xerox giving history on back of each. [MISSING]
      Item #569
    - Leopold, New Haven, CT One in series of five, Group portrait: Wilkins Guard, Co. A. 5th Battalion, Connecticut National Guard pose outdoors; tents and barracks in background. A few women and children also visible. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 10-3/4 x 13-7/8, 1907
      Date in negative.
      Item #570
    - Leopold, New Haven, CT One in series of five, group portrait: Wilkins Guard, Co. A. 5th Battalion, Connecticut National Guard; arranged in large semicircle; two rows. Early 20th century photograph, matted, 11 x 14, 1907
      Item #571
    - Leopold, New Haven, CT One in series of five: Wilkins Guard, Co. A. 5th Battalion, Connecticut National Guard. Child at center foreground. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 8 x 10-1/4, 1907 (Box 18, Folder 834)
      Item #572
    - Leopold, New Haven, CT One in series of five: Wilkins Guard, Co. A. 5th Battalion, Connecticut National Guard, 7 members in uniform posing with rifles in field; 2 are boys; tents in background. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 8-3/8 x 11-1/4, 1907 (Box 18, Folder 835)
      Item #573
    - Underwood & Underwood Regimental portrait; infantry battalion on dress parade in field, tents and barns in background; a few women spectators; a few blacks as part of medical corps far right. Early 20th century photograph, matted 10-1/2 x 22-1/4, 1905
      In negative: "Copyright 1905, Underwood and Underwood."
      Item #574
    - Leopold, New Haven, CT Military group portrait, "New Haven Grays." Large regimental badge center background. Early 20th century photograph, mounted. 10 x 12, 1902
      Photographer's blind stamp, recto.
      Item #575
    - Unknown photographer Interior view: dining car N.Y, N.H. & H. R.R.; tables set, lamps lit, waiters at their stations; head waiter at far end of car. Early 20th century photograph, 6-7/8 x 5-5/8, 1908 (Box 18, Folder 836)
      In ink, recto, "115683, Dining car of the N.Y., N.H. & H. R.R., 1908"
      Item #576
    - Purdy, Boston, MA Boston Latin: group portrait, students and teachers photographed against outside of building. Flags background; sign, "1906" in front row. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 11 x 16-3/4
      In pencil verso, "Boston Latin, Class of 1906. Your brother [?] and his friend Edna Crandau." Photographer identified by engraved label verso.
      Item #577
    - Whitman Studio, Bridgeport, CT Large group portrait of men and boys in suits in front of a Church. Several clerics among the crowd. Early 20th century photograph, framed. 18-1/8 x 22-1/8, 1909
      Dated on badge type ribbon, below photo.
      Item #578
    - Randall, no location Group of young women on steps of institutional building; white rabbit being held, center, foreground; three older men at top of steps by door. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 13-3/4 x 17, circa 1909
      Photographer's identification in negative.
      Item #579
    - Unknown photographer Group of men gathered on and around factory steps, two bicycles right; one left. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 8-1/4 x 10-1/4, circa 1910 (Box 18, Folder 837)
      Item #580
    - Turner Bust portrait of Booker T. Washington in suit looking right, mounted, 9-1/4 x 6-1/2, circa 1910 (Box 18, Folder 838)
      Item #581
    - Carl [?], Jefferson City Group portrait, string band: 13 musicians pose with instruments. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 11-1/2 x 13-3/8, circa 1910
      Item #582
    - Unknown photographer(s) Montage of 13 photographs mounted together in a single glassed frame. Subjects and personalities of Howard University, including groups of the classes of 1914 and 1915; many identified by name. Early 20th century photograph, framed, 22 x 27-3/4, circa 1915
      Many subjects identified by name, including: Dean George Cook, Alma and Clarence Curley, Harry Martin, and "Big Jim Parker, The colored man who captured the assassin of President McKinley."
      Item #583
    - San Fl[?] Company, Philadelphia, PA Group portrait: Knights Templar Band of Harrisburg, PA, photographed at Point Breeze Park in Philadelphia. Band members in uniform, long line, with instruments. Early 20th century photograph, matted, 10 x 20, 1915
      Band identified by drum, center; some band members identified by name in ink recto beneath photograph. Also in ink recto: "Point Breeze Park, Sept. 24, 1915."
      Item #584
    - Ehrhard, Chateau-Thierry, France Four black servicemen at grave of Quentin Roosevelt. Early 20th century photograph, 5-1/8 x 7-1/8, circa 1917 (Box 18, Folder 839)
      Item #585
    - Unknown photographer Bust portrait of black doughboy. Early 20th century photograph, tinted, 10 x 8, circa 1917 (Box 18, Folder 840)
      Item #586
    - Patton Studio, Indianapolis, IN Panoramic group photo of 317th Engineers Band, Camp Sherman, Ohio. In uniform, with instruments, before barracks. Early 20th century photograph, framed, 9-3/4 x 28-3/8, 1918 May 15